Doherty, Robert, Papers /4075
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Robert Doherty Papers
1957-1979
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Doherty, Robert
/4075
14 cubic feet
14 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
3079887
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, January 13, 2016
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 01, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3012: Alice Cook Papers /3038: Robert Doherty Collection of Rochester, NY, Board of Education Conference and SUNY Clippings /4191 AV: ILR School Audio-Visual Department Video Cassette Collection /4297: ILR School Biography Files /4309: M. Gardner Clark Papers 5293: New York State Teachers Association Records 6174/004: NYSUT Field Services Department Files
Doherty, Robert Emmett,1923-; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations --Faculty.
3079887
- ABOUD, Grace, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Academic Collective Bargaining Information Service, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Joe Alder's Work, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Student Advisees, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Editorial: "An American Agenda 2", 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Agreement Between Board of Education of City of N.Y. and the U.F.T., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Agreement Between BOCES and Nassau CSEA, Inc., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bob Ahern, Buffalo Labor-Management Committee, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Albany Law School Police and Fire Talk, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Alternate Compensation Schemes--Materials Used, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Alternate Compensation Schemes, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Alumni University '77, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Alumni University Advisory Board--CB for School Board Member, 1972-1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- American Arbitration Association, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- AAA - Hauppauge Conf. Susann Malin, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- American Association of University Professors, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Arbitration, Final Offer of, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Arizona State Univ. March 1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Article for NYU Journal, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Beaverton Schools Oregon, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Bill of Teacher Rights, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- BOCES - Binghamton Doherty 11/9/77 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Book Reviews, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Boston University, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Boston - USDOL Pers program, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Brooks Paper on Collective Barg. In Sanitation March, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Brown University Rhode Island, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- District Director Search for Capital District, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- California Teachers Association, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Cape, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Carnegie Corporation, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Cazenovia '74, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Center for Information on America, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Center for Urban Development Center Cornell, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Central District Candidates (vitas), 1973 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Chronicle of Higher Education, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Civil Service Study (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Clarion City Univ. of New York, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Collective Bargaining Forum (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Collective Bargaining in Higher Education, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Collective Bargaining in Higher Education, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Collective Bargaining in Higher Education, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Collective Bargaining in the Public Sector, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Committee for Economic Development, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Concentrated Bargaining, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Concord - Municipal Administrators Seminar, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Teacher Contracts (Alphabetic Order), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Cornell Vice President Search Committee, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Council of School Administrators, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- County Officers Conference, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Weinberger County Officers Manual, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- County Officers Concord Hotel, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- County Officers, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- County Officers, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- CSEA/Tompkins County Arbitration (Doherty), 1976 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- CSEA Lake Placid 6/74, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Cunningham, Robert, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Delaware 9/30, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Differentiated Staffing Conference June 24, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Doherty's New Course (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Drotning-Lipsky Paper, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Dyer Manuscript, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Education Law Hearing Panel, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- EFCB Records (Bernard Kabak), 1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Faculty Salaries Study, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Farm Labor Conference, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Federal Legislation, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Fleischmann Commission, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Florida Programs 1978 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Florida 1977 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Florida School Boards Program 1976 Doherty and Dennis (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Ford Foundation, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Four Day Work-Week, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- "Freilicher", 1972 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Gold, Craig-Jr. Sem. In New York City, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Government Manager, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- University Grievance Hearing Panel, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Guggenheim, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Guler Case with Tapes, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Haller, Emil, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Ed Hamilton, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Hanslowe, Kurt, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Hartstein, Barry, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Harvard Educational Review - Tempest on the Hudson, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- University of Hawaii Industrial Relations Center, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Hawaii's Public Employment Relations. Act., 1974 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Horton, Raymond, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Laurie Hunter, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- ICF Incorporated, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Indiana Educ. Employment Relations Board, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- ILR Review (Editorial Board), 1976 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- For Income Tax Purpose, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Institute for Educational Development - I.E.D., 1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Institute for Responsive Education, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Proposal for Institute of Public Employment-Old, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Institute Budget, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Misc., 1971-1975 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Institute Budget, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Institute Budget, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Institute of Public Employment, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Institute Printing, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Interest Arbitration, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Intergovernmental Personnel Act (Box 5, Folder 11)
- State University of Iowa Industrial Relations Central, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- IRRA Meetings and Conferences, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Ithaca Agreement Effective 7/1/72, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Ithaca Journal, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Job Security Program Fall 1975 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Job Security #3 Weisburger, June, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Job Security, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Journal Collective Negotiations in the Public Sector, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Just Cause (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Alex Kashock ILR 699, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- KOJM Bibliography, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Labor Liberal Arts Program Director Search, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- LMDC, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Richard Lalley, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Lieberman, Myron CUNY, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- New Orleans League of Women Voters, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- League of Women Voters Syracuse - 1/16/73, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- League of Women Voters Buffalo - 11/19/73 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Lipsky Confidential, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Local Government Program - Reports, Etc., 1973 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Mary McCormick Ability to Pay, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Memos to Dean McKersie, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Memphis State Univ. Joe Alder (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Donald Macgregor, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Michigan State Univ., 1977 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Montana 1977 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Multi-Employer Bargaining #2, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- National Association of College and Univ. Business Officers (Box 6, Folder 27)
- NAPE, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- National Center for Dispute Settlement, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- NCSL, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- N.E.A., 1970 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Univ. of New Orleans, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- New Orleans Conference, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- NPELRA Conference in Atlanta, GA., 1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- National Center for Study of Col. Barg. In Higher Educ.:, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- National Center for Study of CB in Higher Education - Baruch Col., 1977 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- New Paltz November 8, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- National Education Association, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Proposal - NYC Labor Department, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- New York City Sanitation Strike, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- New York City Teachers Strike 1967 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- New York Times Articles, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- NYSCC/ILR Conference, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- New York State Citizen' Council, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- NYS Council of School District Administrators, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- New York State Education Law, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- New York State School Boards Association, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- New York Times Articles - Clipped, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Office of Collective Bargaining - N.Y.C. Arvid Anderson, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- SUNY Faculty Senate Program - Doherty, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Operational Scope of Bargaining, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Oregon School Boards, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Panel on Grievances (Jeffrey Austin), 1975 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Pennsylvania Project, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Police-Firefighter Arbitration Seminar Feb. 6-7, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Public Employee Bargaining in Oregon, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Pagano, Gerald, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Tenth Anniversary Celebration Conference Law 1977 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- PERB Conferences, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- PERB Minority, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- PERB Minority Training Program 1978 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Training Program for Mediators and Fact Finding, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- PERB/ILR Training Programs 1976 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- PERB Seminars 1975 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- PER Strike Manuscript, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- PERS PSLR Policy Procedure Manual, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- PERS, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- PERS, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Personal Correspondence, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Police and Firefighter Symposium - Albany PERB - ILR 12/76, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- PERB Correspondence, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- PERB Proposal to DOL 1976-77, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- PERB Research, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Lewis Perl's Study, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Helsby Proposal 1976 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- October PERB Conference, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- November PERB Conference, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- December PERB, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Training for Neutrals Oct. Nov. and Dec. 1973 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- PERB Press Conference, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- PERB Symposium on Public Sector Bargaining for Negotiators in Education, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Potsdam, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Productivity File, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Productivity, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Productivity Conference Nov. 16-17, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- New York City Productivity Conference, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Public Education Ass'n., 1976 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Public Employment Relations Research Institute, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Public Sector Program Materials, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Purdue, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Rann 2 Symposium, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Regional Bargaining, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Rhode Island Legislation Covering Public Employees, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Rochester Agreement 7/1/73-6/30/75, 1973-1975 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Rochester Public Schools - General Information, 1973-1975 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Rockland County Research Material, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Rutgers University, 1973-1979 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Sapakie Paper on two Counties in N.Y.S. (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Scher, Seymour, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- School Chiefs Survey, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Misc., 1973 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Questionnaires - Not Coded, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Senate Professional Association, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Joe Shedd Paper (Career Paper), 1979 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Sideographers International Ass'n. of, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Sidney Schwartz N.Y.C. Cola etc. etc., 1979 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- SPIDR-AAA-ILR-Conf. Syracuse - 5/17/79 (Bob), 1979 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- SPIDR '76-'79, 1976-1979 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- SPIDR, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- SPIDR, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- SPIDR, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- SPIDR Program 1974 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- SPIDR Location of, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- SPIDR-State Agency Activities - U.S. Canada, Puerto Rico etc., 1973 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- 7th Annual Conference on Leadership Role of the Trustee, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- State Education Dept., 1976 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- State Education Laws, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- State Government Journal, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Exploring Alternatives to the Strike, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Student Administrative Conferences, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Suffolk County/Suffolk County PBA, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Summers, Roberts, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- SUNY, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- SUNY Personnel Institute Council, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- SUNY Conference 10/72, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- 1976 Symposium "Called off" (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Syracuse Representation, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Texas Ken Tolo - July 10, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Thesaurus, ILR Library, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Toronto, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 19)
- UCLA, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 20)
- University of Calif., 1976 (Box 12, Folder 21)
- UCLA Conference on Public Employee Bargaining 5/24-25/73, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 22)
- UCLA, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 23)
- Educ., 1974 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Educ., 1972-1974 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Paper U.S. Office of Educ., 1973 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- U.S. Dept. of Labor Bureau of Labor Stats Various Articles, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- University of Connecticut, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- University Labor Education Association, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- University of Pittsburgh, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Utica Fact-finding, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- UUP, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- War on Waste 1975 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Washington (State) Evergreen School District #114, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Whyte, Bill, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Wisconsin, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Woodrow Wilson Center, 1964-1974 (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Women in Labor Force, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Yonkers Federation of Teachers Brief (Box 13, Folder 16)
- Oregon, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Walter Oberer, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- SOC Past Practices, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Wingspread Conference, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Oregon-Gen. Correspondence, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Eastern Oregon State College-Classified Col. Bargaining, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Fair Share, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Salary Plans, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Legislative Changes, 1973-1975 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Governance, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- UOTP Fact-finding, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Tounge Point, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Who Negotiates for the Public Employer?, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  Scope and Contents
  Bound
- Collective Bargaining in the Quasi-Public Sector: A Survey of Policies and Practices in the United States, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Arbitration of Representation and Bargaining Unit Questions in Public Employment Disputes, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Constraints on Local Governments in Public Employee Bargaining, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 16)
- A Guide For PERC Hearings, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 17)
- Municipal Collective Bargaining Agreements, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 18)
- 'Good Government' NCSL, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 19)
- 1970 Supplement to Report of ask Force on State and Local Government Labor Relations (Box 14, Folder 19)
- State Aid To Local Government, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 20)
- State Aid To Local Government, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 21)
- Financial Data for School Districts, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 22)
- Overall Real Property Tax Rates, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 23)